tripwolf.com 2019-08-15

# Privacy Policy | tripwolf

**1\. Introduction**

tripwolf GmbH, Pater-Schwartz-Gasse 11A, 1150 Vienna, Austria operates the tripwolf app for iOS and Android, the Phrasebook app for iOS and Android as well as the Website www.tripwolf.com and further domains listed under point 5.

tripwolf takes the protection of your personal data very seriously, and therefore we intend to be fully transparent about which data we use, as well as for what duration and for what purpose, or with which third parties, if any, it can be shared. When you use tripwolf, certain personal data is provided to us. This personal data includes email addresses, IP addresses, device IDs, names and order numbers which are forwarded to us by Apple, Google or Microsoft after a purchase is made.

The privacy policy is an extension of our [terms and conditions](http://www.tripwolf.com/en/page/terms_of_use). In order to use tripwolf you have to agree to the terms and conditions, and thereby also to the privacy policy. This agreement can be revoked any time via written request. Privacy related options can be viewed any time in the privacy settings of the app.

**2\. Registration of a new tripwolf account  
**  
Currently, there are three ways to sign up for a tripwolf account:

a) Via email

tripwolf receives data such as the email address, your password (which is, of course, stored in an encrypted format) as well as an agreement to our terms and conditions, directly from you. If you should provide a name and/or a date of birth, those will be stored as well. This data will not be made available or sold to third parties.

b) Via Google

tripwolf receives personal data such as your email address, and, optionally, your name and/or your profile image, from Google. You give Google the permission to transfer this data to tripwolf during the sign-in process. Should you request the deletion of your account, all of the aforementioned data will be removed from tripwolf’s side. At no point during this process will tripwolf receive access to your Google sign-in information. Other users can only see your username, as part of your reviews in the app or on our website – other personal data such as your name or email address are not publicly visible.

c) Via Facebook

tripwolf receives personal data such as your Facebook ID, email address, and, optionally, your name, profile image, gender and/or age range, from Facebook. You give Facebook the permission to transfer this data to tripwolf during the sign-in process. Should you request the deletion of your account, all of the aforementioned data will be removed from tripwolf’s side. At no point during this process will tripwolf receive access to your Facebook sign-in information. Other users can only see your username, as part of your reviews in the app or on our website – other personal data such as your name or email address are not publicly visible.

**3\. Purpose of data processing  
**  
tripwolf processes and stores data for the following purposes:

1.) Warranty for tripwolf’s services

In order to provide tripwolf’s services, we require certain data from our users, as well as from Apple, Google and Microsoft. Every user device has a unique identifier in our database, to which certain data and events can be associated.

We store the order IDs of in-app purchases together with the aforementioned device records, for the purpose of unlocking or restoring paid app functionality or content. Should the user have signed up for the tripcloud, we also store a timestamp of their sign-in.

When a user registers a tripwolf account they are automatically also using the tripcloud. This allows them to synchronize their purchases and user data across multiple devices. For this purpose, device records become associated with a username. Saved trips, as well as reviews and uploaded photos are associated and stored together with this username.

Should you grant the app permission to access your location information, it will be used for the map functionality both online and offline. Additionally, your current location could be used to send you relevant travel guide recommendations via push notifications.

2.) Improvement and continuous development of the tripwolf app

tripwolf is using third party services (Google Analytics, as well as Google Firebase), in order to improve its own service. This, for example, includes recording click events, which allow us to measure which path through our app the user has taken to purchase or show interest in a product. Based on such information, the app can be adapted, improved and made more user-friendly. While this data is in large part anonymized and aggregated, the third party service providers retain the possibility of storing and transferring this data for their own statistical purposes, also to the territories of other countries.

tripwolf also uses data such as the email address or push notifications to notify the users about improvements and additions to the app.

3.) Advertising, recommendations and offers

tripwolf displays its own as well as third party advertising screens and banners inside the app. In addition to this, other methods of delivery, such as our newsletter and push notifications are also used to inform the user about news and offers. The user has the option of unsubscribing from such messages at any point in time, through the privacy settings in the app.

4.) Prevention of misuse of tripwolf’s services

tripwolf uses collected data in order to prevent fraudulent activities, spam and unauthorized access to its products and services.

If all or significant parts of the company should be sold or their ownership transferred to a third party, it is not excluded that personal information could also be transferred to said third party as part of such a transaction. Additionally, we retain the possibility of transferring personal information to a third party, should we conclude that this is required of us by law (including court orders and summons); to comply with governmental requests; to fulfill the terms and conditions for the use of our service; to protect our rights, privacy, security and assets, as well as those of our employees and our users; to protect our technical operations; and to allow us to employ appropriate legal remedies or to limit possible damages to us.

4\. Which data is collected through use of the app and for what duration?

The user transfers their data through the use of the tripwolf app, which is then stored and used to provide use of the product. In case the user contacts tripwolf through channels outside of the app, such as email, this correspondence is also stored and, in most cases, extended through other information such as device records, app version and operating system version, in order to simplify the process of technical support.

a) Information about the use of tripwolf’s services

tripwolf stores records of the user’s activity, such as in-app purchases, signing in/out with their user account, as well as the synchronization between their various devices. User-specific data is stored until the deletion of the user account, while other data, which can be found in server logs, is removed after a period of 65 days.

b) Storage of data related to the device/internet connection

tripwolf processes and stores server logs for up to 65 days, in order to provide services as well as simplify technical support for our users. The data in question includes the app version, OS version, device ID, device model, IP addresses and sign-in specific data. All data which tripwolf itself stores is transferred, in encrypted form, to the servers of Amazon Web Services in Ireland, and thereby remain within Europe.

c) Statistical data

tripwolf uses Google Analytics, Adjust and various Google Firebase services, in order to analyze usage behavior for the purpose of improving the app, to measure the success of the company as well as to simplify technical support in case of app errors or crashes.

Adjust allows us to measure both internal and external marketing outcomes. Using this tool we are able to measure the number clicks on links displayed both inside and outside of the app, and to see how successfully each of them performed. This service works with anonymized IDs based on a combination of different features (language, device, IP address, timestamp), but which are deleted after a period of 6 hours. Adjust stores the remaining data of its European customers in Amsterdam and Frankfurt.

No personal information is stored using Google Analytics in the app, and the remaining anonymized data is stored for up to 24 months.

Firebase Analytics stores information such as ad clicks, purchase events and additional details about the usage of the app for up to 60 days.

Firebase Remote Config helps us to perform testing of new and/or experimental functionality in our app and to measure its success with the help of our users, to finally be able to choose the best possible variant. The already collected data will be deleted at the latest 30 days after a request for deletion is made.

Firebase Crashlytics is a service which helps us to quickly discover errors in the app and to provide effective technical support to our users.

Google LLC fulfills the data privacy and protection requirements of the EU by maintaining a Privacy Shield Framework license, and is thereby permitted to store user data outside of Europe. The license can be found [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI).

The consent to use of the aforementioned services can be revoked at any time through the privacy settings in the app.

d) Location data

tripwolf uses location data in order to provide the map functionality, as well as to send personalized recommendations for nearby places to the user. This data is not stored, instead it is just processed to provide various functionality. The permission to use this data can be changed at any time in the system settings of the user’s device.

e) Customer support

Should the user contact tripwolf using the app or the website, it is possible that certain identifying features (in addition to the email address) are sent along with the message, in order to provide the user with the optimal conditions for support. This includes the device model, device ID, app version, OS version and user ID, if applicable. This data is transferred to and stored by Zendesk, Inc.

Zendesk, Inc fulfills the data privacy and protection requirements of the EU by maintaining a Privacy Shield Framework license, and is thereby permitted to store user data outside of Europe. The license can be found [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOjeAAG).

f) Marketing activities

We use the email address provided to us by you, as well as the permission to send push notifications to your device, in order to notify you about offers and news.

The email address, together with the user language, as well as information which allows us to send you personalized messages (e.g. last downloaded travel guide, device platform, tripwolf Unlimited status) is transferred to us during subscription to our newsletter. This additional information is only sent to us if you have signed up for the tripcloud. We store this data as long as you are subscribed to the tripwolf newsletter. Should you unsubscribe from the newsletter, your data will be deleted from our MailChimp account.

You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time, by clicking the link at the end of every newsletter email, as well as through the privacy settings in the app. 

The permission to send push notifications is given in a platform-dependent manner. You can change this permission at any time through the privacy settings in the app.

5\. Website  
  
In addition to the app, tripwolf also operates the websites hosted under the following domains: tripwolf.com, tripwolf.reisen, tripwolf.guide, trip-wolf.com, tripwolf.net, tripwolf.de, tripwolf.it, tripwolf.fr, tipwolf.com, tripwolf.eu, tripwolf.tv, tripwolf.cc, tripwolf.us, tripwolf.biz, tripwolf.mobi, tripwolf.info, tripwolf.org, tripwolf.co.uk, as well as all associated subdomains.

5.1. Cookies

tripwolf’s websites use cookies in order to provide and simplify the use of their functionality. Through the cookies, data is stored on the user’s device, for example, to notify the website that a user is signed in, and thereby simplifying its usage.

The user can delete the cookies at any time, as well as change their browser settings so that certain websites are not allowed to store cookies. In doing so, the user may limit or disable some functionality of the website.

In addition to cookies, tripwolf also uses tracking pixels, which operate similarly to cookies. A more detailed description of this statistical data collection can be found under point 5.2. Information about cookies used for marketing purposes can be found under point 5.3.

**If you want to disable tracking by Google Analytics, you can opt-out here.**

5.2. Usage statistics

Google Analytics is used on the websites listed under point 5., for purposes of measuring usage behavior, particularly clicks, and to detect changes in market trends. tripwolf anonymizes your IP address and does not share your personal data with Google Analytics. You can delete or block cookies at any time, or notify us about your preferences by changing your user settings at any point in time.

The anonymized data is stored for up to 24 months.

5.3. Advertising

tripwolf displays its own as well as third party advertising through partners such as Google AdSense, DoubleClick and MairDuMont.

These third party providers use cookies in order to show personalized advertising based on the user’s interests during previous visits to the website.

6\. Deletion  
  
The user has the right to request deletion of their account at any time. This request can be sent in writing, via an email to support@tripwolf.com.

As part of the account deletion, all personal data stored by tripwolf, as well as that stored by third parties, will be irreversibly deleted. Processing of such a deletion request may take up to 30 days.

In addition to that, every user has the right to correct errors in their data or to request a report with an overview of all of their data which had been gathered by tripwolf up to that point. This request also must be sent in written form to the above mentioned email address. A request for this data collection report can only be fulfilled before or in absence of a request for account deletion.

7\. Final provisions  
  
Exclusively Austrian law is applicable. The court responsible for legal matters is that in Vienna, Austria.

Any change in the privacy policy shall become effective on the date given in the latest version of the document. No notification of change is required. Should a user not agree to the terms and conditions or the privacy policy, they may request deletion of their account at any time.

tripwolf GmbH cannot be held responsible for unauthorized access to user data (e.g. through system failure or hacking).

tripwolf GmbH, Vienna, Austria  
Version of the privacy policy: 9th of May, 2018
